Murad Yusri

Cairo, Egypt | Mobile: +20 1030930723 | <u>MuradYusri08@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/murad-yusri707 | behance.net/muradyusri | app.uxcel.com/ux/5XZZK930NIHB

SUMMARY

I am a Product Designer with more than 2 years of experience working in a variety of industries including health care, government, utility providers, finance, art, business, sports, e-commerce, services, and insurance. I have the knowledge and abilities to leverage the UX design thinking process to create effective and efficient experiences with usable designs that align with the company's goals and user demands. I'm searching for a position as a Product Designer where I can leverage my business modeling skills to establish product strategy and my design abilities (research, interaction design, and UI) to develop products that are valuable, usable, and desirable.

EXPERIENCE

Gulf Union Al Ahlia Cooperative Insurance Co. - Riyadh, KSA

UX designer

October 2022 - Present

Provider Health Portal (B2B Web Application)

As an Insurance firm, my duty is to create a B2B Health portal for providers, beginning with the user flow and concluding with the Ui Design.

The task is to create a web application with multiple inputs that is user-friendly and comfortable for heavy daily usage, as well as interactive in a simple and informative interface.

Insurance (Mobile Application)

My role is to create a mobile app for users that covers all insurance services, beginning with user flow and concluding with a design system and style guide for the UI.

The objective is to build the mobile application in a popular neomorphism style with a simple and user-friendly interface while maintaining accessibility standards without complexities.

Digital Magna Co. - Cairo, Egypt

Product designer

June 2022 - Present

The Drive (Mobile App & POS App)

- Starting with business meetings and evaluating solutions with stakeholders, conducting user interviews with users, and finally drawing using low-fidelity wireframes.
- Create the interface for the mobile app.
- Create a POS app for cashiers and station administrators.
- Create backlogs and key performance indicators (KPIs) for the developer team.

AlMuhami (Mobile app & Web Site)

- Creating Interaction design for B2C and B2B Mobile apps and websites, As a legal platform the challenge was to maintain user experience history with familiar actions such as reservations, and to create clear methods to help users in the B2C app.
- In the B2B app, the challenge was a clear and interactive system to help lawyers control and manage their appointments and requests.

Al-Ahly FC (Mobile Application)

- My challenges as a product owner in this project were evaluating the final design with the low-fidelity wireframes and making sure it is meeting the business requirement.
- Enhance the user journey in the loyalty program by Dsquares in the app.
- Create product backlogs and KPIs for the developer team.

MYND Clinic (Web Site)

- Creating psychologist website reservation and payment.
- Analyse SRS with the business team and stakeholders to build personas and meet business goals.
- Create user scenarios, user flows, information architecture, and wireframes, and conduct User testing.
- Build Design system contains:
 - * Style and design guidelines (Icons, Colors, Spacings, Fonts, and Illustrations)
 - * Component libraries : (CTA, elements, Images, Navigation, Cards, UI controls, and templates models)
- User Interface Design the app and prototype.
- Hand over the development team and revise the output to insure quality.
- Presentate all apps to the stakeholders.

Trichem Co. – Cairo, Egypt Ux designer

Dec 2021 - May 2022

- Building an E-commerce App for the company's products to maximize sales and expand in a more pro way, research the market, and analyze the competitors to get the minimum value proposition.
- Survey 90% of the customer, conduct interviews with 15 % of customers to gain user needs and insights, and assure that the product value matches the needs and the business goal.
- Create user scenarios, user flows, information architecture, and wireframes, and conduct User testing.
- Rebranding the logo concept and the colors to maintain product trust with the customers.
- Build Design system contains:
 - * Style and design guidelines (Icons, Colors, Spacings, Fonts, and Illustrations)
 - * Component libraries : (CTA, elements, Images, Navigation, Cards, UI controls, and templates models)
- User Interface Design the app and prototype.

SEC Co. – Khobar, KSA *Ui designer*

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

- Enhancing user experience and design with the Development team to keep up with the turning online during Covid-19 and the new features that the company provides.
- Design Wireframe for (HASIBTI) app
- Rebuild Design system Style (Icons, Fonts, and Illustrations) and component libraries
- User Interface Design for the website.

TEBAQ Construction CO., – Dammam, KSA Project Manager Drafter

Apr 2016 - Jan 2021 Jul 2014 - Apr 2016

- Managed several teams of more than 100 in 3 locations (Qatif, Dammam, and Khobar), ranging from Labours, and supervisors to project engineers, and collaborated with the executive manager, SEC, and contract owners.
- Launched new executing methods with my team which grew the monthly revenue by 150% in the first ten months (representing 90% of company revenue).

- Created a reporting program in 2017 for the Daily Productivity which helped to analyze group activities and reduce the waste of duty time to 30% and increase the performance by 50%.
- Overhauled the obsolete legacy source code of two production applications, resulting in increased usability and reduced run time performance by 50%.
- Worked with many consultants such as Saudi Electrical Company, Emirate Of Eastern Province, PWC Consultant UK, Saudi National Guard, and Sheraton group in initiating contracts and submitting work.

LEADERSHIP

Information Technology Institute (ITI) - Mansura, Egypt *Track Leader*

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

• Spearheaded 35 students during the intensive program, Follow up on tasks and schedules and coordinate between managers, instructors, and students.

Change Management & Continuous Improvement Dept - SEC, Khobar-KSA *Team Leader*

Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Led my team to the top 4 teams during the Department study on Preparing the Youth Cadres.
- Ranked First in the (problem statement and efficient solving) program.

EDUCATION

Information Technology Institute (ITI) – Mansura, Egypt
Diploma in UI/UX, Computer Science; Postgraduate Intensive Training Program.

Nov 2021

Zagazig University – Zagazig, Egypt Bachelor in Commerce, Business Administration May 2013

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

Business Modeling (Strategy, Value Proposition), Cognitive human psychology, User Research methodologies, Competitor Analysis, Data Analysis, journey maps, user scenarios, User Flow, Interaction Design, Wireframe, User Interface Design, and Prototype.

Managerial Skills: Project Planning, Timeline Control, Leadership, Agile Methodologies

Software: Adobe XD, Figma, Sketch, InVision, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Lucidchart

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Languages: Fluent in English, Arabic

Certifications & Training:

- * The Leading Skills for Project Managers, SEC Training Center (Jul 2015)
- * The 7 Habits for Managers Essential Skills and Tools for Leading Teams, franklin covey (April 2016)
- * Google UX Design Certificate (ongoing Coursera)